# Andrés Romero

PhD computer vision and parallel architectures

#### **About**

6 rue de Chateaudun 94200 lvry-sur-Seine France

**○** 0178542907 **□** 0615231394

■andresrommier@gmail.com

### **Languages**

Full working proficiency in spanish, english and french

### Programming/ architectures

C and C++ (12+ years), Matlab (8+ years), Python (4+ years), PHP (4+ years), Javascript, IATEX

OpenMP, SIMD (SSE, AVX, Neon and Altivec)

Notions of data science and massive data mining using MapReduce (Hadoop) and R

TI C6000 and C5000 Panda boards, Raspberry PI's and Intel ULV platforms

## Operating systems

Strong Linux/Unix skills, Mac OS X, Windows

## **A** Interests

I am lecturer and researcher from the **Parallel Systems team** at the Laboratoire de Recherche en Informatique from Paris Sud University XI, where I work on the **design**, **acceleration** and **implementation** of **computer vision** algorithms.

The key goal of my research is to develop high performance algorithms for **visual object detection**, **tracking** and **texture description** for real-world problems. The algorithms I have worked with require comprehensive understanding of a broad set of domains: **machine learning**, **software engineering**, **computer architecture** and **statistics**.

In total, I have more than 8 years of research experience working with signal and image processing algorithms in embedded architectures. I am familiar with **ARM architectures** (ARM Cortex A9 and A15) and the **Texas Instruments C6000 DSP** family. On those platforms I have implemented many image, voice and audio processing algorithms. During my PhD I worked on the acceleration of computer vision algorithms on desktop and embedded platforms using **OpenMP** and **SIMD** instructions sets (SSE, Neon and Altivec).

Other fields of interest to me are **data science**, **natural language processing** (NLP), **data mining**, **information theory**, **complexity theory** and **cybernetics**.

## Education

2010-2013 <b>Ph.D.</b> in Co	omputer Science	Laboratoire de Recherche en	Informatique.	Université Paris Sud
------------------------------	-----------------	-----------------------------	---------------	----------------------

Advisors: Lionel Lacassagne and Michèle Gouiffès

Real-time multi-target tracking: A study on color-texture covariance matrices and descriptor/operator switching.

The results of this work were considered for the ITEA/Spy european project.

2006–2008 M.Sc. Signal Processing Instituto Politécnico Nacional (IPN)

**Advisors**: Héctor Pérez Meana and Mariko Nakano Miyatake Subject: Acoustic active noise controllers in TMS320C6713DSK platforms.

2000-2005 **Telecommunications Engineering** Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México (UNAM)

Advisor: Bohumil Psenicka

Graduation project: Acoustic active noise cancellation.

2000 **High-school** Centro Universitario México, Mexico City

Specialization in mathematics and physics

## (E) Experience

2013-2014	Université Paris Sud, Orsay Faculty of Sciences	Invited researcher and teacher		
	Research work: Covariance descriptor algorithm implementation on "Many-core" architectures (Xeon-Phi)			
2012-2013	ITEA/Spy European Project Tracking and pedestrian re-identification module, project in collaboration between 0	R&D engineer CASSIDIAN, EOLAN, ENSTA and IEF		
2009	Minalum de México S.A. de C.V.  Controller development for a brushless DC motor using PIC's	R&D engineer		
2009	Czech Technical University in Prague, Czech Republic	Visiting Student		

Hosted by Prof. Pavel Saradnik

2007-2009	<b>Computer security department, DGSCA, UNAM</b> Emergency response team (CERT) system development.	Software engineer
2006-2007	<b>Qualcomm, Omnitracs, Mexico City, Mexico</b> Satellite and GPS surveillance system operator	Operations engineer
2004	Electoral Institute of Oaxaca, Oaxaca, Mexico  Pre-electoral results system for the 2004 governor and local congress elections	Software engineer

#### About

6 rue de Chateaudun 94200 lvry-sur-Seine France

■andresrommier@gmail.com

✓ andresrommier
O andresromero
in romeromier

## **Languages**

Full working proficiency in spanish, english and french

### Programming/ architectures

C and C++ (12+ years), Matlab (8+ years), Python (4+ years), PHP (4+ years), Javascript, IATEX

OpenMP, SIMD (SSE, AVX, Neon and Altivec)

Notions of data science and massive data mining using MapReduce (Hadoop) and R

TI C6000 and C5000 Panda boards, Raspberry PI's and Intel ULV platforms

## Operating systems

Strong Linux/Unix skills, Mac OS X, Windows

## **Teaching experience**

2013-2014 ATER (Invited researcher and teacher)
Courses:

- SIMD instructions for image processing,
  - On-line data representations (XML, DOM, XPath, XSLT),
  - Relational data bases (SQL),
  - Advanced C programming,
  - · Logical component and computer architecture,
  - Scilab.

2012-2013 **Laboratory teacher** 

Université Paris-Sud, France

Université Paris-Sud. France

Courses: SIMD instructions for image processing.

2005-2008 **Laboratory teacher** 

Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México, Mexico

Courses:

- Digital signal processing algorithm implementations on DSP architectures,
- · Digital and analog filtering.

## Publications

## **Articles in peer-reviewed journals**

Color tracking with contextual switching: Real-time implementation on CPU

F. Laguzet, A. Romero Mier y Terán, M. Gouiffès, L. Lacassagne

Journal of Real Time Image Processing (JRTIP) Special Issue on Real-Time Color Image Processing (2013). Springer, 2013

H, Perez-Meana, A Hybrid Noise Canceling Structure with Secondary Path Estimation

A. Romero, M. Nakano-Miyatake

WSEAS Recent Advances in Systems, Communications and Computers (2008) pp. 194–199. 2008

## International peer-reviewed conferences/proceedings

Total Bregman Divergence for Multiple Object Tracking.

A. Romero, M. Gouiffès, L. Lacassagne

IEEE, International Conference on Image Processing (ICIP), 2013

#### Real-time covariance tracking algorithm for embedded systems

A. Romero Mier y Terán, L. Lacassagne, A. Hassan Zahraee, M. Gouiffès

Conference on Design & Architectures for Signal & Image Processing (DASIP) proceedings. 2013

#### Enhanced Local Binary Covariance Matrices ELBCM for texture analysis and object tracking

A. Romero, M. Gouiffès, L. Lacassagne

MIRAGE 2013, Berlin, Germany. ACM International Conference Proceedings Series, 2013

Covariance Descriptor Multiple Object Tracking and Re-Identification with Colorspace Evaluation

A. Romero, M. Gouiffès, L. Lacassagne

ACCV 2012 Workshops, Part II, LNCS 7729 proceedings, 2012

#### Feature points tracking adaptive to saturation

A. Romero, M. Gouiffès, L. Lacassagne

Signal and Image Processing Applications (ICSIPA), 2011 IEEE International Conference on, 2011

#### Synthesis of the Low-pass and High-pass Wave Digital Filters

B. Psenicka, Francisco J. García-Ugalde, A. Romero Mier Terán *ICINCO-SPSMC*, 2008

#### Synthesis of digital structure by matrix method

B. Psenicka, F.G. Ugalde, L.E. Salguero, A. Romero

Proceedings of the 7th IASTED International Conference on Signal and Image Processing, 2005

## **SE** References

Lionel Lacassagne, Associate Professor (MCF HDR)

Laboratoire de Recherche en Informatique (LRI) Université Paris Sud

▼ lionel.lacassagne@lri.fr

**\**+33 0169154124

. . . . . . . . . . . . . . . .

Michèle Gouiffès, Enseignant Chercheur Laboratoire d'Informatique pour la Mécanique et les Sciences de l'Ingénieur Université Paris Sud

michele.gouiffes@u-psud.fr

**\( +33 0169858113** 

### Programming/ architectures

Full working proficiency in

spanish, english and french

About

France

6 rue de Chateaudun

94200 lvry-sur-Seine

✓ andresrommier@gmail.com

**\** 0178542907

**1** 0615231394

in romeromier

Languages

**y** andresrommmier **Ω** andresromero

C and C++ (12+ years), Matlab (8+ years), Python (4+ years), PHP (4+ years), Javascript, LATEX

OpenMP, SIMD (SSE, AVX, Neon and Altivec)

Notions of data science and massive data mining using MapReduce (Hadoop) and R

TI C6000 and C5000 Panda boards, Raspberry PI's and Intel ULV platforms

## Operating systems

Strong Linux/Unix skills, Mac OS X, Windows

#### • • • • • • • • • • • •

Rubén Aquino Luna,
Information Security Sub-director, DGTIC, UNAM
Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México
raquino@seguridad.unam.mx

**4** +52 55 56223064

. . . . . . . . . . . . . .

Bohumil Psenicka, Full-time definite C-level Professor Facultad de Ingeniería, UNAM, Mexico City, Mexico Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México

pseboh@servidor.unam.mx

**\**+52 55 56223064